Francisco José Palmero Moya

Mathematical Physicist & Scientific Programmer

Working at TU Delft

♣Personal website Github franciscopalmeromoya ☐ franciscopalmeromoya@gmail.com Van Embdenstraat, 2628 ZP 👂 Delft, Netherlands +34-

I am a mathematical physicist with a master's in Research in Artificial Intelligence. Since May 2023, I have been working as a Scientific Programmer at the Nynke Dekker Lab in TU Delft, where we focus on understanding the DNA replication process of different biological systems.

I obtained my B.Sc. in Physics at the University of Córdoba (Spain) in 2022 studying the mathematical formalism of spinors. I also complement these studies with a B.Sc. in Mathematics with a strong focus on subjects closely related to physics. I recently completed a M.Sc. in Research in Artificial Intelligence and collaborated as a research assistant where we focused on stellar dating using Bayesian hierarchical models.

I have a broad interdisciplinary set of interests, including Lie groups theory, spinors, evolutionary computing, quantum programming, and emergent phenomena. I consider myself a curious and proactive person. I am an eager reader of philosophy and literature in my free time.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Research in Artificial Intelligence

National University of Distance Learning; GPA: 3.36

Bachelor of Science in Physics

University of Córdoba; GPA: 3.16

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

National University of Distance Learning; GPA: 3.00

Online Oct 2022 - Sep 2023 🛗

Córdoba, Spain 9

Sep 2017 - Jul 2022 🛗

Oct 2018 - present

EXPERIENCE

Technische Universiteit Delft

Scientific Programmer & Data Analyst - Nynke Dekker Lab

May 2023 - present

- Delft. Netherlands **9**
- Research in Biophysics: Our lab focuses on understanding DNA replication using state-of-the-art biophysics.
 - * Lead the development of microscopy data accuisition and analysis software.
 - * Provide data analysis support to students and researchers with diverse backgrounds.
 - * (Co-)author publications with other researchers.

National University of Distance Learning

Researcher - Dr. L. M. Sarro & Dr. J. Olivares

Remote

Sep 2022 - Sep 2023

- o Research Collaboration Fellow: Our aim is to define and implement a Bayesian hierarchical model able to determine the ages of star clusters and associations through two age dating techniques: isochrones and Lithium abundance.
 - * Bayesian inference and Hamiltonian Monte Carlo.
 - * Astrophysics of stellar evolution.
 - * Publishing results as first author.

University of Córdoba

Research Assistant - Dr. Rafael M. Rubio & Dr. Magdalena Caballero

Córdoba, Spain 9

Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

• Research Collaboration Fellow: Researched on mathematical foundations of spinors (particles with semi-integer spin), namely Lie Groups and its representations, within the Mathematics Department of the University of Córdoba.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish: Mother tongue
- English: Full professional proeficiency
- German: Professional working proeficiency

PROGRAMMING SKILLS SUMMARY

- Languages: Python, R, SQL, Latex, Fortran
- Tools: TensorFlow, PyMC, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, Matplotlib, MATLAB, ggplot2, Tableau, Excel

Academic Exchanges

University of Granada

Granada, Spain

Sep 2020 - Jun 2021



• SICUE: I had the chance to attend lectures on topics like:

* Quantum Field Theory, General Relativity, and Quantum Information Theory.

University of Leipzig

Physics

Physics

Leipzig, Germany

Oct 2019 - Jul 2020 🛗

- Erasmus+: I could boost my social managing skills with people from different countries. I attended lectures on:
 - * Statistical Physics, Solid State Physics, and Mathematical Physics

PUBLICATIONS

- Francisco J. Palmero Moya, J. Olivares, and L.M. Sarro. Bayesian Inference of open cluster ages from photometry, parallaxes and Lithium measurements. Astronomy & Astrophysics, submitted (2023)
- Zhaowei Liu*, Edo van Veen*, Humberto Sánchez, Belén Solano, Francisco J. Palmero Moya, Kaley A. McCluskey, Daniel Ramírez Montero, Theo van Laar, and Nynke H. Dekker. A biophysics toolbox for reliable data acquisition and processing in integrated force-confocal fluorescence microscopy. ACS Photonics, submitted (2023) $(* = equal\ contribution)$

Honors and Awards

• I have been awarded an academic exchange grant by the University of Córdoba as top best student in Science Faculty within SICUE exchange program. (2020)